Raymond Ray

4630 118th Street SE, Everett, WA 98208 · (206) 349-9680 (cell) · (425) 379-8088 (home) Raymondray269@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/raymondray

PROFESSIONAL HIGHLIGHTS

Capital One's IT support for entire Northwest region.

Projects included opening Capital One's Technology Center – 501 Eastlake Ave - Network, multiple Audio-Visual rooms, two AV common areas, 200 user's stations & phones.

Kickstarted Capital One Seattle's MAC experience - previously purely Windows OS; now 80%/20% MAC/HP -Site MAC SME.

Opened & kickstarted Capital One's Service Bar – sported as model for Capital One Enterprise Opened & kickstarted Capital One Bellevue & South Lake Union CAFEs.

Decommissioned old Legacy ShareBuilder/ShareKeeper 600 user site - Network, multiple Audio-Visual rooms, two AV common areas, 600 users & phones.

Re-opened Capital One Irving, CA Car Finance site – NW & phones – 100 users.

Manage Investing software accounts across US - sites in Plano, Wilmington, Newark & Mclean

EXPERIENCE

9/2012 - 10/2019

IT/IS SUPPORT, CAPITAL ONE

First three years as Deskside Services Tech team supporting 700 Internal users while last four years as sole IT/IS Support for 300 internal & 400 external users.

Duties included hardware & software, networking, audio visual support. inventory management & technology infrastructure duties.

Responsible for resolving all 1st/2nd Level & beyond to successful resolution; first level resolutions ~ 96.7% & all escalations met all SLAs.

Tasked with merging Sharebuilder (existing Investing/Banking startup) into Capital One's network & systems; i.e.: tested all existing software, OS configurations & processes.

Windows XP to Windows 7 & Windows 10 migrations; MS Office XP through 2016 (cloud) migration finally entire Tech Center to GSuite.

Image, configure, distribution & management of MAC systems.

Resolve difficult customer concerns by working collaboratively with multiple departments.

Identify trends in hardware, software or systems - research & proactively apply resolutions

Document issues, resolutions & processes - HPSM, Oracle, ServiceNow, etc. records systems.

Author training documents, play books, check lists & training - Trained entire investing departments in Investing Software (ShareKeeper).

Supported Lexmark, HP & Ricoh secure print enterprise printers

Author training documents, play books, check lists & training - Trained entire investing departments in Investing Software (ShareKeeper).

Supported Lexmark, HP & Ricoh secure print enterprise printers.

2/2012 - 9/2012

IT/IS SUPPORT, EXPEDITORS INTERNATIONAL

Contract Position – Windows OS upgrade & MS Office migration.

2/2009 - 2/2012

IT/IS SUPPORT, PEMCO INSURANCE CORPORATION

Kept all systems operating optimum - 300+ users @ Seattle Headquarters.

Performed first level core troubleshooting on hardware/software problems.

Provided technical solutions to user's issues; answer questions, provide assist.

Documented user problems, resolutions & solutions for future reference

Communicated highly technical information to both technical & non-technical personnel

Upgraded site (Windows XP) to Windows 7

Maintained network/incident management including detection, triaging, mobilization and incident resolution efforts.

Resolved difficult customer concerns by working collaboratively with multiple departments. Identified trends in hardware, software or systems - research & proactively apply resolutions Documented issues, resolutions & processes - HPSM, Oracle, ServiceNow, etc. records system

CERTIFICATES / LICENSES / DESIGNATIONS

A+ Service/Network Tech
Clear Designated Subject Teaching Credential
Community College Lifetime Teaching Credential
Council Postsecondary/Vocation Authorization
IBM/Dell/HP Service Technician Authorization
CNA Novell Systems Administrator

EDUCATION

California State University, Long Beach, California Technical Teaching Credentials – Information Systems

Mount San Antonio College, Walnut, California Associates – Technology Associates – Nursing

SKILLS

Twelve years plus experience providing Enterprise IT level I & II support Capital One, Expeditors International & Pemco Insurance.

In-depth knowledge of Windows and Max OSX operating systems - installing, troubleshooting, and configuring OS.

In-depth knowledge of both Microsoft Office & GSuite applications

Strong knowledge of HP, Lexmark & Ricoh printers.

Worked with ZOOM, SLACK, SKYPE, LOGMEIN, VNC, etc. for remote user support.

Excellent verbal and written communication skills

Extensive work in Active Directory, policies & groups.

Skilled with Windows Registry & MAC Keychain, JAMF & Mac management tools

Involved experience in SCCM/CCM to imaged, deploy, push/remove software and manage assets.

Install, configure & maintain Window & MAC servers.

Work in Airwatch for mobile device (iOS, Android) configuration and support.

Linus experience.